Keshav Raj

keshav.rajsspn@gmail.com | +91-9576640200 | linkedin.com/in/k-e-s-h-a-v | github.com/k-e-s-h-a-v

SUMMARY

Data Engineer with 3+ years of experience in building high-performance data platforms, specializing in decentralized architectures (DataMesh) and real-time data visualization. Successfully led teams, was quick to adapt to challenging environments and contributed to product acquisition

EDUCATION

Bhagalpur College of Engineering, Bhagalpur

Jul 2018 - Sept 2022

B. Tech in Electrical Engineering

CGPA: 8.2

Sainik School Punglwa Nagaland, Ministry of Defence

May 2010 - June 2017

Science, High School Education

Percentage: 81.2

EXPERIENCE

Infor Jul 2024 - Present

Hyderabad, India

• Software Engineer Jul 2024 - Present • Integrated Apache Superset using Delta Lake to the DataMesh platform for real-time data visualization.

o Built an invoice processing system with Qwen to extract data that feeds an event-driven, configurable data entry pipeline, reducing SLA from 48 hours to 1.5 minutes.

albanero (acquired by Infor) Jun 2021 - Jul 2024

Hyderabad, India

• Software Engineer II (6 months)

Jan 2024 - Jul 2024

- Key contributor to a **state-of-the-art DataMesh platform**, later acquired by Infor.
- Slashed memory usage by 90% in the CSV-to-Excel pipeline. eg: 52 GB to 4 GB for ≈ 3 million records.
- Enabled multi-CSV merging into a single Excel file, with each CSV as a dedicated sheet.
- Team Lead (8 months)

May 2023 - Jan 2024

- Led a team of data analysts to deliver high-impact products, including two key projects—one was live in just 6 weeks.
- Built a data mastering system using the Jaro-Winkler algorithm for duplicate detection.
- Standardized entity names using **NER** with **spaCy**, and integrated **Loqute** for **address verification**.
- o Conducted internal training sessions on our **DataMesh platform**, teaching teams how to use its **decentralized** architecture and scalable workflows.
- Software Engineer I (8 months)

Sep 2022 - May 2023

- Built a dynamic **SQL** query generator to search/filter millions of records.
- Software Engineer Intern (1 year 4 months)

Jun 2021 - Sep 2022

- o Developed Identity Access Management (IAM) for DataMesh, including role-permission logic.
- Authored feature for real-time status updates for data transformation workflows using Socket.io.
- o Implemented multi-theme support in a SaaS platform, standardized SCSS practices, and gained hands-on experience with **JavaScript**.

PROJECTS

• Code Folder Summary

Visual Studio Code Extension

- o Developed a VS Code extension to provide a quick overview of file types in a project with a sidebar summary, file type overview with icons, counts, and percentages, and the ability to ignore folders.
- Implemented theme-aware UI and ensured no setup required for immediate use.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript

Libraries/Frameworks: PySpark, FastAPI, Flask, Docker

Tech: Apache Superset, MongoDB, Git, AWS Athena, Delta Lake (with Parquet)

CERTIFICATES

An Introduction to Artificial Intelligence § Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms using Python & Data Analytics at E & ICT Academy &

IIT Delhi

IIT Madras

IIT Kanpur